Man, this week's storyboard is good too.
いや 今週のネームも面白い
Your enthusiasm really shines through.
新妻君の気合いが ビシビシ 伝わってくるよ
Never mind that.
そんな事より
How did I do in the rankings this week?
今週の順位 どうでしたか
CROW came in 1st again.
「CROW」 今週も1位だ
Is that so?
そうですか
I'll keep working hard and come in 1st next week, too.
次も1位取れるように頑張ります
yu
me
Dreams, dreams, dreams, dreams
ka
na
e
ru
ta
bi
ko
wa
re
te
yu
ku
me
As soon as I reach my goals, it all falls through again
na
ze
so
re
de
mo
ma
ta
So why do I run...
bo
ku
wa
sa
ga
su
ha
shi
ri
tsu
zu
ke
ru
...and search in spite of that?
hi
sa
shi
bu
ri
ni
de
atta
We met after such a long time
"
fu
n
i
ki
ka
watta?"
"Has the mood changed for us?"
tsu
ki
hi
wa
na
ga
re
ta
da
rou
So much time has passed
"
a
no
ko
ro
no
ho
u
ga
ta
no
shi
so
u
"
"It seemed like more fun back then"
ta
ku
sa
n
na
ku
shi
ta
We've lost so much
so
n
na
ko
to
wa
ki
zu
i
te
ru
n
da
I already know that, though
sa
ke
bi
tsu
zu
ke
ro
mo
ga
ki
tsu
zu
ke
ro
Don't stop screaming, don't stop struggling
da
re
no
ta
me
ni
na
n
ka
mou
i
da
rou?
You've done enough for others
ma
da
tsu
ta
e
i
ko
to
ga
a
ru
ma
da
I still, still have something I haven't told you yet
yu
me
no
sa
ki
ni
wa
yu
me
shi
ka
na
i
Beyond each of my dreams lies yet another dream
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)出品 仅供交流学习之用 禁止用于商业用途
---诸神字幕组---
台本: 共由         翻译: 新人&poopy       繁化: 烨语
校对：绫女       时间轴：Color
Serialization and Prevention
CROW's been ranked 1st three weeks in a row.
Climax
of
the
Sky
Prison
saga!!
Climax
of
the
Sky
Prison
saga!!
それにしても 「CROW」3週連続1位か
Niizuma is incredible.
新妻さん すごいな
Yeah.
Catching up to him won't be as easy as we made it sound.
追いつくって言っても 簡単には いかないだろうな
Apparently, Niizuma's been devoting a lot of time into revising his storyboards lately.
新妻君 最近は 何日もかけ ネームを描き直してるらしい
Seriously?!
あの新妻さんが
His storyboards?!
ネームを
Yeah. He's been working on them for days on end.
ああ 目の色変えて 作業しているそうだ
I wonder what happened.
どうしちゃったんだろう
Maybe he's trying to egg us on?
もしかして 俺たちを奮起させるために
Well, knowing that CROW is ranked 1st does make me feel more motivated...
確かに 俺も「CROW」が1位を取ったって聞いて
へこんでらんないと思った
See?
だろ
It's Niizuma's way of lighting a fire under us!
新妻さんなりのエールだって
Yeah!
だな
We've gotta surpass him in the rankings and return the favor!
だったら すぐにでも追いついて 恩返ししてやろうぜ
Yeah!
はい
Here's CROW and NATURAL's manuscripts.
「CROW」と「NATURAL」の原稿です
Thank you!
お疲れさまです
Nothing has changed this week, either.
今週も いつもどおり
Was I worrying too much?
俺の取り越し苦労だったのかな
It's a seven year old promise, after all.
7年も前の約束だし
Um, Niizuma, congrats on CROW coming in 1st.
あの
新妻君
「CROW」1位 おめでとう
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Think you can do something about NATURAL, too?
「NATURAL」の方も どうにかなんないかな
I haven't been slacking on the art. What's the problem?
ちゃんと描いてますけど 駄目ですか
There's nothing wrong with the art.
絵の手抜きはないんだけど
But it's dropped in the rankings ever since the anime ended,
アニメが終わった途端 順位が下がったし
and this week it's 10th.
今週なんて 10位
I know you're doing the art for both, but...
作画は同じ新妻エイジなのに
It's because the story for NATURAL isn't interesting.
「NATURAL」は 話が面白くないですから
I'm not the story writer.
原作 僕じゃないですから
If you want it to be popular,
人気 取りたかったら
you and Akina have to make the story compelling.
秋名先生と港浦さんで 面白い原作 作って下さい
R-Right.
はい
Niizuma's got a point.
新妻君の言うとおりだ 最近の話は 面白くない
The latest chapters are pretty dull.
The story's turned into an endless repetition of
defeating bad guys, each one stronger than the last.
やっつけたらまた それより 強そうな敵の繰り返しだからな
Yes, it's the same pattern over and over again.
ですね ワンパターン
You two sure don't pull any punches.
2人で ハッキリ言ってくれますね
The story might improve if I'm allowed to make changes.
僕が勝手に話 変えていいなら 少しは良くなるかもですけど
But I can only change so many things.
変えるにも限界があります
Akina has her pride, after all.
秋名さん プライドが高いですし
Yeah, no kidding.
そうなんだよな
Forming a relationship with her similar to what Ashirogi Mutou has won't be easy.
なかなか亜城木先生みたいな以心伝心コンビにはなれないです
At least NATURAL's manga volumes are still selling well...
まだ 「NATURAL」のコミックス 結構 売れてるんだけどなぁ
Do you think Niizuma doesn't like the way NATURAL is dragging on?
新妻君 引き延ばし感が嫌になってるんじゃ
Yeah.
確かに ピークは過ぎてるんですけどね
It's certainly past its peak.
I'm finding it hard to breathe when it's just the two of us, Nakai.
中井さんと2人でいると 息苦しい
It's like there's less oxygen in here than there should be.
絶対 酸素が薄くなってる
It's not like I actually want to be your assistant.
俺だって 平丸君のアシスタント 好きでやってんじゃない
That's no reason to let the quality of your art drop, Nakai.
だからって 手は抜かないでくれたまえよ 中井さん
It won't match unless I drop my
quality down to the level of your art.
I don't know
what your goal is,
but please
spare me!
手を抜かなきゃ 平丸君の絵には合わないんだよ
Oxygen
Why do you insist on talking to me like we're buddies?
大体 何で僕が 中井さんを「さん」付けで
中井さんは「君」なのだ
Oxygen
Aren't I top dog here?
僕の方が立場が上ではないのか
I get the feeling you think pretty highly of yourself.
何か中井さんは常に偉そうである
Believe me, I'd rather not speak to you like we're friends.
「君」どころか 呼び捨てにしたいくらいだからな
Why not?
何で
Because things are going well
between you and Aoki, obviously!
蒼樹さんと うまく やってるからに決まってるだろ
Nakai! Are you telling me you haven't given up on her?!
中井さん まさか まだ 蒼樹さんの事を諦めてないのか
Oh, I just got an idea! I think we can use it.
あっ アイデアが 付け足そう
I did give up on her, but I can't help but feel jealous!
諦めてはいるが 羨ましすぎるんだよ
Do you have any idea how I feel, having to work with you?!
そんなやつに使われてる身にもなってみろ
What I'd give to have a girlfriend...
彼女 欲しい
Why don't you ask Mr. Yoshida for advice?
では 吉田氏に相談してみては
Huh?
It's no secret that my relationship with Aoki
started by following advice from Mr. Yoshida.
何を隠そう 蒼樹さんとの仲も吉田氏に相談したのがきっかけで
Really?!
本当か
Speak of the devil.
うわさをすれば
What?
何
Nakai? With a girl?
中井君に
女性を
Impossible.
無理だ
I know, right?
ですよね いくら吉田氏でも こればかりは
Not even you can help him, Mr. Yoshida.
Wait a second! If I can make this work...
いや 待てよ
うまくいけば
Do you really want a girlfriend?
本気で彼女が欲しいと
O-Of course!
も もちろん
You'd be required to follow a diet plan that I would create for you.
それには まず
僕の作るダイエットスケジュールをこなすのが条件になる
However, that would lessen a
negative influence on Hiramaru,
しかし そうなると 今までのように食いまくってもらい
namely the financial burden of
supporting your overeating habits.
平丸君に経済的プレッシャーを与え
ネガティブにさせられなくなるが
Is that all you care about, Mr. Yoshida?!
そんな事を考えていたのか 吉田氏
But it's true that no matter how much you eat, that feed—I mean, food,
だが いくら中井君が食おうと
そのエサ いや 食費など
is not a major source of negativity for Hiramaru at this point in time.
今の平丸君にとっては 大した ネガ要因になりえないのも確か
More important is the risk that you would succumb to obesity-related diseases.
それより 成人病で倒れられても やっかいというもの
Your skills as an assistant are practically wasted on Hiramaru.
アシスタントの腕は 平丸君には もったいないくらいだからな
Nakai.
中井君
If you truly intend to follow my teachings,
本気で 僕についてくる気があるのなら
then I'll rise to the challenge of
transforming you into a Super Manga Author.
君を スーパーマンガ家にする事を挑戦してみてもいい
Super Manga Author?!
スーパーマンガ家
Yes! Like a manga Super Saiyan!
そうだ マンガのスーパーサイヤ人的な
We'll turn you into a first rate manga
author in mind, manners, agility, and looks.
一流マンガ家としての
精神
礼儀
ルックス
身のこなし
You'll be able to turn the head of any woman—Aoki included!
女性なら 誰でも
いや あの蒼樹先生も振り返らせるほどのマンガ家を作り上げる
You already have the skills. I know you can do it!
もともと 腕はあるんだから いけるはずだ
Mr. Yoshida! What are you saying?!
吉田氏 何 言ってるんですか
I'll give it a shot!
僕 やってみます
N-Not you too, Nakai!
な 中井さん あんたまで
All right!
よしっ まずは 朝晩10ｋｍのランニングだ
Start by running 10 km, mornings and evenings!
Yes, sir!
はい
No way!
そんな
Forgive me, Hiramaru.
許せ 平丸 これも 君のネガティブを継続させる愛のムチ
This tough love is necessary to keep your negativity flowing.
And if I can corrupt Nakai at the same time, that'll be two birds with one stone.
そして 中井が化ければ 一石二鳥
Oh! This makes CROW's fourth consecutive week at 1st!
「CROW」4週連続1位
CROW is doing unbelievably well.
「CROW」すごいな
It's popularity is the real thing.
この人気は本物だ
It's because he's making things exciting by having all the characters participate in a final battle.
全キャラ出して 最終決戦かよってくらいの盛り上げ方だからな
PCP's in 3rd.
「PCP」3位
Road Racer GIRI's anime just started, and now the manga is ranked right below us.
アニメが始まった「ロードレーサーGIRI」が すぐ下に
Once Seigi no Mikata's drama adaptation starts, it should skyrocket to the top of the rankings!
「正義の三肩」もドラマが始まればドーンと上がるはずだ
Hey, Yuujirou.
そうだ 雄二郎さん
What's up?
何
Ashirogi sends their thanks.
亜城木君が感謝してました
Huh?
CROW's top ranking gave them some motivation.
「CROW」が1位を取ったのが励みになったと
So that's it!
そうか そういう事か
I-Is something wrong?
な 何がですか
Remember what I told you?
ほら お前には教えただろう
About earning the right to end a manga?
「マンガを1本終わらせる権限」
Yes...
I was worried that Niizuma might be going for that,
それが欲しくて頑張ってたら やばいと思ってたんだけど
but it looks like he only has Ashirogi's best interests in mind.
亜城木君のためだったんだな
If that's why he's so set on being in
first, he'll never come out and say it.
それなら1位取っても 何も言わないはずだ
You came in 1st again.
今週も1位だ
I see. That's good.
はい よかったです
It's business as usual, then.
やっぱり いつものとおりだ
Also, Ashirogi wants you to know that CROW's top ranking has motivated them.
それと 亜城木君が「CROW」の1位が励みになったと伝えてほしいと
Ashirogi?
亜城木先生が
Yeah.
What are they thinking?
何を言ってるんですかね
亜城木先生
What do you mean? They just wanted to thank you.
何って 礼だよ 礼
I'll become a Super Manga Author!
なるんだ スーパーマンガ家に
Now
Open
Welcome!
いらっしゃいませ
Yuujirou, CROW is 1st again!
Editorial Department
Shounen Jack
Jack SQ
X Jack
雄二郎さん
また「CROW」1位ですよ
Huh? But today's Thursday...
今日 木曜日じゃ
Wait, rankings are out today since the holiday break starts tomorrow, right?
明日から連休だから もう出てるのか
That's right. I left them on top of your desk.
What God Gave Me is... 7th.
「神様がくれた」7位
Thanks!
Never Reaching You is 5th.
「僕には通じない」 5位
All right! This is good for now.
よし 今はここでいい
First place for five weeks in a row!
5週連続1位
GIRI's at 3rd. The anime must have bumped it up.
「GIRI」も3位 アニメの効果があったか
My time has finally come!
来たな 俺の時代
I'm Hattori Yuujirou, editor of the 1st and 3rd ranked manga!
1位と3位担当の服部雄二郎でーす
Just make me a team leader already!
いいかげん 班長にして下さーい
Refusing on the basis of my youth is old-fashioned!
「まだ若い」とかいう考えは 古いと思いまーす
He's so full of himself!
図に乗りすぎじゃ
Hard to argue with the 1st and 3rd rankings, though.
1位と3位じゃ 文句も言えない
I'm off to Fukuda's house!
福田君のとこ 行ってきまーす
All right! Seigi no Mikata is in 6th!
よし 「正義の三肩」6位
Miura, you don't have time to be rejoicing.
港浦 浮かれてないで「NATURAL」を何とかしろ
Do something about NATURAL.
Oh, right.
はい
GIRI beat us in the rankings?
「GIRI」に上に行かれたか
PCP placing 4th isn't so bad,
「PCP」4位は上出来だが
but it can't outrank a manga that has
an anime, let alone catch up to Niizuma.
新妻君どころか
やはり アニメ化された作品にはかなわないのか
I'll never stop living on the edge!
「俺はいつでもGIRIGIRIを狙うぜ」
It feels like he's going so fast!
すっげえ スピード感
It's only episode 3 and it's already this exciting!
アニメ3話で この盛り上がり
With this, the manga's rankings and volume sales are sure to go up!
これで マンガも コミックスの売り上げも アゲアゲ 間違いねえ
Great timing.
チッ いいところで
You came in 3rd place this week!
今週も3位だぞ
We're finally in the top three!
おおっ ついに ベスト3
Getting first place might not be just a dream, after all!
こりゃ もうトップも 夢じゃないですね
Well, there's quite a gap between you and CROW.
You've got your work cut out for you.
いやあ 「CROW」との差は結構あるからな なかなか
You sure look happy.
何 にやけてんすか
Since you're already editing both, you won't give a damn if GIRI passes CROW, will you?
「CROW」も担当してるから
「GIRI」が抜いても 雄二郎さん的には 意味が ねーんだろうけどな
That's not true!
そんな事ないって
I'd be thrilled if GIRI got the top spot!
「GIRI」が1位になれば 本気で喜ぶし
Ideally, newer manga should surpass long-running ones.
新しいマンガが 長く続いたマンガを抜くのが 理想だと思ってる
But it'd be really hard to surpass CROW.
でも 「CROW」 抜くの大変っすよね
It's come in first place for the last five weeks.
5週連続1位なんすから
Niizuma being so set on coming in 1st had me feeling anxious for a while.
新妻君が1位にこだわるから 一時は ハラハラしたけどな
Why's that?
どういう事っすか
Didn't Nonaka tell you?
野中君には話してなかったっけ
Niizuma asked for the right to end a manga he
hates if he ever became the no. 1 author in Jack.
「1位を取ったら 嫌いなマンガを終わらせる権限をくれ」って 新妻君が
Huh?
Needless to say, I told him he couldn't do that.
もちろん 「そんなの駄目だ」って僕は言った
But the Chief told him, "We'll talk about it if you still feel that way once you've become our magazine's main attraction."
編集長も 「そんな事は 真の看板になった時 まだ そう思ってたら」
って事で 話をつけたんだが
So what was the manga Niizuma wanted to end?
で 新妻先生が終わらせたいマンガって 何なんすかね
I really wanna know!
すげえ 興味ある
I haven't asked him, you know.
言っとくけど 聞いてないよ
But this was decided when he was serialized seven years ago.
でも 連載前じゃ 7年くらい前の話ですよね
Maybe the manga he wanted to end is already over.
もう終わってるマンガかも
Yeah... And at this point in time, it'd probably be NATURAL.
そうだな
今なら 「NATURAL」かもな
Why?
何でですか
He said the story's boring and
follows the same pattern over and over.
「原作がつまらない ワンパターンだ」って言ってたからな
Are you sure you should be telling us this?
いいんすか
そんな話 ベラベラしゃべっても
It's okay. I know Niizuma won't bring that deal up again.
新妻君は もう 嫌いなマンガを終わらせるなんて言わないって 分かったからな
His fixation on being 1st is just to motivate Ashirogi.
今の1位は 亜城木君にやる気を出させるものだし
Besides, he's matured during his years of being serialized.
連載していくうちに 新妻君も成長したって事だ
Wow!
すげえ
CROW's come in first place five weeks in a row!
「CROW」5週連続1位
The story's getting exciting with the introduction of an all-out war.
総力戦って感じで 盛り上がってますからね
And then we have PCP, which will never get an anime.
それに比べて 「PCP」ときたら
アニメにもなんないし
Saikou, don't you think it's about time we started thinking about another manga?
サイコー マジで考えてみない
そろそろ もう1本
An unorthodox battle story with a mainstream character...
王道キャラで 邪道バトル
I've drawn the all-important
mainstream character a few times.
肝心の かっこいい王道キャラ 少しずつ描いてるけど
Have a look.
これってのが
Wow!
This is pretty cool!
これ かっこよくね
This too!
これも
No, they're not good enough. I don't want to compromise.
駄目だって 妥協したくないし
What's wrong, Niizuma? This is unexpected...
どうしたんだ 新妻君 急に
I spoke with someone at the reception desk.
ちゃんと受付で 手続き 済ませました
I didn't hear anything about that.
僕 聞いてないけど
I came to meet with the Chief Editor.
編集長に会いに来たです
I received approval.
OKもらいましたけど
The Chief?
編集長
Could he be...
まさか
You're the only one left, Falcon!
あとは 隼 お前だけだ
You're damn good, Giri. I always knew you were!
ギリ
お前は やっぱり サイコーだ
You never cease to amaze me, Falcon.
さすがだぜ 隼
That's a perfect line.
完璧なライン取り
Our moves are in perfect harmony.
こっちの 揺さぶりにも 全く同時ねえ
But such perfect driving isn't my...
だが 俺には そんな上品な走りは
Go!
いけー
All right, here it comes!
よーし 出るぞ
My killer move! Triangle...
必殺 トライアングル
Fly Cornering!
フライコー
Yuujirou's here to pick up the manuscript.
雄二郎 原稿 取りに来たな
Right in the middle of the anime, again.
また アニメ 放送中に
Things were just getting good.
それも 一番いいとこで
Only a madman would think of a move like that!
Can't you let us watch the anime in peace?
Sorry to keep you waiting. Now, let's go!
アニメくらい ゆっくり見させてくれよ
Didn't I tell you?
I always win!
Sorry.
ごめん
What's your problem?
何すか あれ
Some girl wouldn't give you the time of day or something?
女にでも ふられたか
That can't be it. He's usually all
smiles, even when he gets rejected.
いえ しょっちゅう ふられてますけど いつも元気でしたよ
Yuujirou, CROW and GIRI had good rankings this week.
雄二郎さん 今週の速報 「GIRI」も「CROW」も良かったよな
Yeah.
うん 今のところは また「CROW」が1位かもしれないな
With the way things are looking,
CROW will be 1st again.
And why do you look depressed about that?
何で 「CROW」1位で あのポーズ
What a downer.
暗っ
I think I know...
まさか
Yuujirou, you must be upset over Master Niizuma.
雄二郎さん 新妻師匠には困ったもんすね
"Upset" doesn't even begin to describe it.
困ったなんてもんじゃ
I knew it!
やっぱり
えっ あっ 何が
What?
Master Niizuma brought up the right to end a manga he hates, didn't he?
新妻師匠 やっぱり 「嫌いなマンガ 終わらせる権限くれ」って言いだしたんだろ
What're you talking about?!
なっ 何を言ってるんだ
Got any proof?!
何を証拠に
Wh-Where's your manuscript?!
げ 原稿どこだ 原稿
Here.
Thanks.
もらっていくよ
Listen you better....
いいか くれぐれも想像だけで
curb your imagination.
And don't spread any... strange rumors!
変なうわさ 立てないでくれよ
He's so easy to read.
分っかりやすー
I wonder which manga Master Niizuma wants the right to end.
だとしたら 新妻師匠は 何を終わらせたいと言ってたんだ
Last week, Yuujirou said it'd probably be NATURAL.
先週 雄二郎さん 「NATURAL」だろうって言ってましたよねぇ
Miura!
港浦さん 打ち合わせ やる気あるんですか
Are we having this meeting or what?
Huh? Oh, yeah...
うん あるけど
The anime's over and the manga's ranking has plummeted.
アニメが終わって 急に順位 落ちましたね
That's why I told you to be careful.
だから言ったじゃないか 気をつけようって
Excuse me.
失礼します
Hello?
もしもし
It's Aoki.
蒼樹です
Sorry, but I'm in a meeting right now.
すみません
今 打ち合わせ中で
I'll call back later, then.
じゃあ また後で
On second thought, if you have
something to tell me, you can say it now.
いえ 用件だけなら 今でも 大丈夫です
Okay...
では…
A gathering at Fukuda's place?
福田さんの所に集まる
Um, I'm not part of the so-called Team Fukuda.
あの 私は いわゆる 福田組では
But it's to discuss the possibility of Niizuma ending NATURAL...
それが 新妻さんが「NATURAL」を終わらせようとしているかもという事なので
I understand.
分かりました 6時ですね
6 PM, right?
We don't even know if Niizuma's
actually been given the right to do this.
でも まだ新妻さんが 何かを終わらす権限をもらったって
決まったわけじゃないんですよね
That's true.
まあな
But it's also true that Niizuma showed up at the editing department on Monday and spoke to the Chief Editor.
月曜に新妻君が編集部に現れ
編集長と話した事は確かです
I heard this from Mr. Yoshida.
吉田氏から聞きました
Since they spoke in a separate room,
別室で2人きりで話されてたため
even Mr. Yoshida, a team leader,
doesn't know what they talked about.
その内容は 班長の吉田氏にも分からないとの事です
In other words, only Niizuma's editor, Yuujirou, knows.
つまり 新妻師匠の担当である雄二郎だけに 内容が伝えられた
And you know how Yuujirou's been acting.
その雄二郎が あの態度だ
It does seem likely that he was
granted the right to end a manga.
マンガを1つ終わらせる権限が与えられたと考えても
おかしくない
And that would be NATURAL?
それが 「NATURAL」
No, maybe it's Never Reaching You!
いや もしかしたら「僕通」かもしれない
Hiramaru, that's not something you should be happy about!
平丸さん うれしそうに言わないで下さい
I still find it hard to believe that they'd give him that right just because he came in 1st a few times.
でも アンケートで1位を何回 取ったからって
人のマンガを終わらせる権利が与えられるとは思えません
And the idea that he'd choose to end NATURAL is just speculation.
それが 「NATURAL」というのも 推測でしか
Yeah. It's partly his manga, after all.
そうだな
一応 自分のマンガなんだし
Nothing can come from discussing this here!
ここで こんな話をしていても しかたありません
I'm going to ask him directly .
直接 新妻さんに聞きに行きます
So it's true that you asked for the right to end a manga you hate?
じゃあ 「嫌いなマンガを終わらせる権限をくれ」って言ったのは
本当なんだな
Yes.
はい
And did you get it?
で その権限はもらえたのか
They'd never give him the right do something like that.
もらえるはずないじゃないですか
But they did.
もらいましたけど
With some conditions.
条件付きですけど
Conditions?
条件
I have to get first place ten weeks in a row.
10回連続1位にする事
So I only need to come in first place for five more weeks!
あと5週1位を取り続ければOKです
I'll definitely get 1st in the next five weeks and end a manga.
必ず あと5週 1位取って 終わらせます
Ten weeks in a row...
10週連続
He came in first with a large lead in this week's initial ranking.
今週の速報も ダントツ1位
That means he actually has only four more weeks to go.
あと4週という事か
Tell us what manga you want to end!
それより 終わらせたいマンガって 何だ
Is it mine?
僕のなのか
It is, isn't it?
だろ そうだろ
The one I want to end...
終わらせたいのは
is CROW!
「CROW」
CROW?
Hiramaru?
平丸さん
I knew it!
やっぱり
Wasn't it supposed to be a manga you hate?
嫌いなマンガじゃなかったのか
I do hate it.
嫌いですけど
You do?
嫌い
I hate not being able to end something in the way that I want.
自分で終わらせたい形で 終わらせられないのは大嫌いです
I know that the editing department
doesn't want to end a popular manga.
僕だって 人気マンガを編集部が終わらせたくないのは 知ってますし
The magazine is trying to make a profit, and I understand that.
商業誌ですから 当然だとも思います
But before I started drawing, I made a resolution.
けど 僕は描く前から決めてました
I resolved to end my manga when I want to: at the
height of its popularity, in the coolest way possible.
終わらせる時期は 自分で決め
一番人気の時に かっこよく終わらせる
It looks like I'll be able to do that, and I couldn't be happier.
それが できそうで うれしいです
The Chief wanted me to continue the manga if possible, but he came around soon enough.
編集長も最初はできるなら もっと 続けてほしいと言いましたが
すぐ分かってくれたです
And that's when he said you had to come in 1st for ten weeks straight.
そこで 10週連続1位って条件を出されたわけか
Not exactly.
それは ちょっと違います
After I come in 1st for ten weeks in a row, I then have ten weeks to wrap the story up and end it.
10週連続1位取ったら
そのあと10週でまとめて終わらす
That's the condition I gave.
これは 僕の方から出した条件です
The Chief Editor accepted it.
その条件を 編集長が のんでくれたです
What happens if you don't come in 1st for ten weeks in a row?
もし 10週連続1位を取れなければ
Then I can't end the series.
やめないです
It wouldn't be cool if another manga got first place.
もし1位を 他のマンガに取られたら かっこよくないです
Should that happen, I would try again to come in 1st for ten consecutive weeks. Then, I'd end my manga.
その時は もう一度10週以上 不動の1位に挑戦し
成し遂げてから終わらせます
If I can't do that, I have to keep drawing the series until it gets canceled.
それができなければ 打ち切りまで 描くしかないですけど
Getting canceled or staying in first place...
不動の1位で終わるか 打ち切りか
Such extremes.
極端だな
Excuse me.
失礼します 「NATURAL」でないのなら 私は帰ります
If this don't concern NATURAL, I'm leaving.
She hasn't changed.
相変わらずだな
Niizuma
Should you continue drawing a popular manga just because it's popular,
人気マンガだから続けるべきか
or should you end it when you want to?
自分の終わらせたいところで 終わらせるか
It's a difficult question.
難しい問題ですよね
I can understand wanting to end it in the best way that you can.
作品を最高の形で終わらせたいって気持ちは 分かるけど
But it'll hurt Shounen Jack if CROW ends.
「少年ジャック」的には ここで「CROW」が 終わったら いてーだろうな
The anime still ongoing.
アニメも続いてんだ
If it was me, I wouldn't end my manga while it's still popular.
僕だったら 人気あるうちは 終わらせない
It'd be such a waste!
もったいないですよ
I think you should continue while it's still popular.
僕は 人気あるうちは 続けるべきだと思いますが
Are you serious?!
何 言ってんだ 君は
Niizuma already has all the money he could ever need!
新妻君は もう遊んで暮らせるだけのお金があるんだ
He should end his manga now and just enjoy himself!
とっとと やめて遊ぶべきだ
Work is just meant to earn you
enough money to live on, anyway!
そもそも労働というのは
生活するために必要な賃金を得るものであって
Hiramaru, that's not what we're talking about here.
平丸さん そういう話じゃなくって
Right.
あっ はい
Well, even if you end CROW, you've still got NATURAL.
まあ 「CROW」やめたって
「NATURAL」があるからな
But Akina writes NATURAL.
でも 「NATURAL」は 原作 秋名さんですし
I'd like to do another manga of my own one day.
やっぱり いつかは もう1本ですけど
I'm not against you ending CROW the way you want.
俺は「CROW」を自分の理想の形で 終わらせる事に反対じゃないが
But I don't want you to end it this way, either.
何か このまま終わらせたくねぇ
I feel the same.
僕も福田さんと同じ気持ちです
You're the artist we've always looked up to.
新妻さんは ずっと 僕が目標にしてきた作家です
I know how you feel,
新妻さんの気持ちも分かりますが
and excuse me for saying this, but I don't want you to end it now.
勝手な事 言わせてもらえば
今 終わってほしくない
I won't let you!
終わらせてたまるかって気持ちです
Yeah.
だな 新妻さんを抜きたいと思って ずっと やって来たんだ
We've always wanted to surpass him.
I don't want things to end without us ever having succeeded!
抜く前に終わってほしくない
Yeah.
I see. If he ended it now, it'd be
like he quit while he was ahead.
そうか このまま終わらせたら なんか勝ち逃げされた気分だ
Which means,
って事はだ
if we don't want him to end it, we need to overtake him!
やめさせたくなければ
新妻師匠を抜けばいいんだな
That's correct.
そうなりますけど
So sorry, but CROW ain't ending!
残念だけど
「CROW」は終われねえな
Because I'm gonna pass you!
俺が抜くからな
You can't.
抜かせませんけど
No, we can!
いや 抜いてみせる
Right, Saikou?
なあ サイコー
Yeah!
I understand how Fukuda and Ashirogi feel.
福田さんや 亜城木さんの気持ち分かります
Even if I'm not against Niizuma ending it as he wants to,
新妻さんの理想とする終わらせ方に 反対しなくても
as his rival, I want to surpass him.
ライバルとして抜きたい
We all can agree on that.
その気持ちは 私も同じです
Yeah, I want to surpass CROW, too.
確かに 「CROW」抜きたいですよね
I want to pass him and prevent him from ending it.
抜いて終わらすのを阻止したい
It'd be awesome if I were able to do it.
それができたら最高だし
かっこいい
What are you talking about?
みんな 何を言ってるんです
CROW is at the height of its climax! You can't win!
「CROW」は 今 最高に盛り上げてるところですから抜けません
I didn't throw out manuscript after
manuscript only to lose to the likes of you guys!
ネームや原稿を放り出してここに来てる人たちなんかに
抜けるはずがないです
Now you've said it, Master Niizuma.
言ってくれるじゃねえか
新妻師匠
Coming here has gotten us fired up.
でも ここに来たおかげで 俺たちにも火がついたぜ
I'll take you on!
受けて立ってやる
I won't let you end your manga in such a cool way!
そんな かっこいい終わらせ方は させねえ
Yeah! Never!
絶対にさせない
How interesting.
面白いです
Forget five weeks.
あと5週なんて言いません
If anyone manages to beat me even once before I finish my final manuscript,
僕が最終回の原稿を描く前に誰であろうと 一度でも抜いた人がいたら
I won't end CROW!
「CROW」はやめません
He won't end it if we beat him!
抜ければ やめない
We have eight more weeks... No, seven!
チャンスは あと8 いや7週
It's a challenge!
勝負です
You're on!
はい
do
u
shi
te
da
ro...
i
tsu
mo
so
u
sa
Why, I wonder?
chi
ka
zu
ku
ta
bi
ka
ra
ma
wa
ri
no
yu
me
Whenever I am close to fulfilling my goals, all effort becomes fruitless
ma
e
wo
mu
i
te
shi
ga
mi
tsu
i
te
sou
su
ko
shi
zu
tsu
We walk ahead, hold each other, and with little things
ya
ku
so
no
a
ba
sho
he
to
sa
e
ai
na
ga
ra
we support each other to reach what we promised
ji
shi
n
ga
ta
ri
na
i
to
ki
wa
mu
ne
ni
te
wo
a
te
When we lack confidence, we put a hand to our heart
bo
ku
ra
ga
tsu
zu
t
ta
pe
e
ji
yo
mi
ka
e
so
u
and reread the pages we assembled into a story
kyo
u
ma
de
so
shi
te
a
su
he
to
tsu
zu
i
te
yu
ku
no
sa
They lead up to today and continue into the morrow
ta
i
se
tsu
na
yu
me
ga
ka
na
u
so
no
hi
ma
de
We will always be ourselves
a
ri
no
ma
bo
ku
ra
de
zu
tto...
until the day that our dreams come true
Next Time
Preview
I accepted Master Niizuma's challenge!
新妻師匠と勝負 燃えるぜ
I'm pumped!
I want to get first place with Hiramaru.
私は 平丸さんに1位を取ってほしいです
Next time: Front and Center.
Front and
Center
次回 巻頭とセンター
I'll win and achieve my dream!
ぶっちぎりで 夢を達成してやれ